Charles Boudousquie

Software Engineer Specialize in Tools and Al Development

https://www.linkedin.com/in/charles-boudousquie 425-429-5260

<u>charlesboudousquie@gmail.</u>com https://github.com/charlesboudousquie/Portfolio

SUMMARY

I am a driven Software Developer with 2 years of industry experience, and 1 year volunteer programming with independent game developers. Programming experience includes Graphics, Particle Systems, built from scratch 3D editors and Behavior Trees. I am passionate about writing top- quality maintainable code, and I am eager for opportunities that combine team driven development and individual component ownership.

COMPUTER SKILLS

Languages

- C++ (3 years professional, 8 total)
- Python(2 years professional)

Operating Systems

Windows, Linux

API

- OpenGL 4.3, ImGui / ImGuiZmo
- Assimp, Bullet3, GLFW, SDL
- Berkeley Sockets, Apache Thrift, Pybind11

Tools

- Visual Studio, VS Code, Git
- Unity, Unreal Engine 4, Buck Build Tool

Soft Skills

Working on large collaborative codebases.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science in Real-Time Interactive Simulation – Redmond, WA 9/2016 – 4/2021

DigiPen Institute of Technology

Basic Networking

- OpenGL 3D Rendering, Reflection, Refraction, Texture, and Deferred Shading.
- · Al path planning and problem solving

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Cornered Rat Software 9/2021 – 4/2022

- Generalist Programmer (bug fixing)
- Full time (40 hours a week)

Meta (XR Maps Team, Contracted by Advantis Global with a 2 year limit) 4/2022 to 4/2024

- Software Engineer
- Reduced C++ build times to 1/8th
- Wrote Pybind11 code to connect our C++ and Python code.
- Wrote custom, fast Thrift serialization

SCHOOL PROJECTS

Engine Programmer 1/2018 – 4/2018 **Gun Garden** – 2D Action Bullet Hell

- Developed Customizable Particle System
- Created Menus and Tutorial level

3D Editor Programmer 9/2018– 3/2019 **Project Abyss** – 3D First Person Light Mixing Puzzle Platformer

- Researched and integrated tools for custom 3D video game editor
- Build a graphics framework with OpenGL
- Added Translation, Rotation, and Scale Gizmos
- Integrated Bullet3D physics
- Ray Picking to move objects with mouse
- FPS Camera and Editor Mode Viewing
- Undo/Redo functionality (save state)

Charles Boudousquie

Software Engineer Specialize in Tools and Al Development

https://www.linkedin.com/in/charles-boudousquie 425-429-5260

<u>charlesboudousquie@gmail.com</u> <u>https://github.com/charlesboudousquie/Portfolio</u>

Al Programmer Reformed Studios 9/2019 - 4/2020

- Implemented efficient, shared behavior tree system
- Created Behavior trees with said system

Personal Project 5/2020 – 8/2020

 Created full flight 3D Octree navigation